<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Kevin Linder]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kevinlinder.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kevinlinder.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-21T04:45:38+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kevinlinder.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kevin Linder]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charter Install Hell With a Tivo]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2014/05/11/charter-install-hell-with-a-tivo/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-11T04:57:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2014/05/11/charter-install-hell-with-a-tivo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You know that saying about installing cable being up there with getting a root canal? Well sadly it's true. This post will mostly serve as assistance for any others that might happen to be in my situation. It also has the added benefit of allowing me to vent from the complete incompetence of the installers employed by Charter.</p>
<a class="anchor" id="read-more"></a>
<p>The worst part is I already had Charter Communications out to my house. I previously had them come out and install Internet. It went as smoothly as it could go when the installer finds that you don't have a line present and he has to run one from the telephone pole in your neighbors yard. Most of the time he took was simply to get the cable to my house. With that done the actual hooking up the Internet went fairly smooth and error free.</p>

<p>Sweet.</p>

<p>Once I get my TV and entertainment center hooked up, I realize that the rabbit ears I have used for quite a number of years to get free HD channels, is not good enough for my current location. Thus I needed to get cable TV. So call Charter and get an appointment set up. I get the usual, they will be there between 3pm-5pm and it might take 2+ hours to complete.</p>

<p>Fast forward to 3pm and I get a phone call telling me they are waiting for me at the door. I open the door and then tell the operator that there is no one at my door. She then proceeds to say ok and then hang up. I'm baffled but figured I'd hear the door knock soon. So I wait.</p>

<p>Long story short, they are ringing the bell at 727 instead of my house at 721.</p>

<p>I try not to get annoyed as it can be a simple mistake or perhaps he didn't see the ONE that is a SEVEN.</p>

<p>Although I had the cable newly run from the pole for Internet, it seems they have to get on the pole in order to do god knows what else. They get that handled and now start working on the actual cable installation inside.</p>

<p>After some time they call me into the living room and tell me they can't seem to get my Series3 Tivo working. All the Tivo keeps doing is stating it is downloading the channel list. Just a blue screen with that icon.</p>

<p>In order to use a Series3 Tivo, I needed two CableCards. They installed MCards or multi-stream cards, although I could have used SCards (single stream cards) those are not readily available and by putting MCards into a Series3 Tivo they will revert to a SCard. Thus why I need two of them. In addition to the CableCards I also needed a Digital Tuner. This is a box that communicates with the Cable Company to tell them which cable channel I have requested to view. At which the send the signal down and communicate back to the Digital Tuner where it can be located in the downward stream of cable. (note: this is a very simply way of describing it but you get the point I hope). Then the Digital Tuner will output the signal to the Tivo which the CableCards then decrypt the encrypted data.</p>

<p>The installer (and his intern which he is training) proceeds to tell me he has done everything correctly and my box is getting the signal. He proceeds to show me his tool as if some gibberish on his screen means something to me and that it will all make sense. Being in software myself, just because something has a ping, doesn't mean it is set up correctly. We spend the next almost hour of going through looking at the CableCard details as well as he switching the slots they are located in. He unplugs the tuner as well as various other things only to plug them back in. I realize he is looking to me to solve it and is at a point where he is stuck and doesn't know what to do.</p>

<p>His advice? I need to go buy a new Tivo. Because that must be the issue. My Tivo is broken. It is now 5pm and he is stating he will give him his phone number and I can call him tomorrow and he will come out with his "manager" and work on it. Although I'm pretty sure he's just trying to find a way to get out of there by 5pm. I let him leave and let the Tivo try to finish downloading the channel list.</p>

<p>After leaving it for hours, I realize it's not working and unplug everything. I go to bed knowing I'm going to call Charter the next day and either get it completed or cancel my service.</p>

<p>The next day when I call Charter, I complained about what happened and very quickly got put on the VIP 'ticket system'. I didn't know that existed but I had someone calling me to make an appointment while I was STILL ON the phone with customer service. Why can't ALL service be VIP?! Nonetheless I made an appointment for them to come out on Friday. Since it's Thursday and they won't be out till the next day, I make a point to try to figure out the issue when I get home that night.</p>

<p>Getting home, I start the debug session. After about an hour I had it figured out and working. I didn't know which I was more, upset that this was something they were unable to figure out, or happy that I was able to fix it and finally have cable. Either way here is what they did wrong and I had to fix for them:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Cable was put in the ANT IN of the Tivo (and not the CABLE IN)</li>
  <li>I added a cable splitter to the cable coming from the wall</li>
  <li>Ran one of the cable to the CABLE IN of the Tivo</li>
  <li>The other cable ran to the CABLE IN of the Digital Tuner</li>
  <li>Plugged the Digital Tuner USB into the Tivo</li>
  <li>Unplugged the cable the installer had run from the CABLE OUT of the Tuner to the CABLE IN of the Tivo (in my case he had done it to the ANT IN)</li>
</ul>

<p>It seems when using a digital tuner that a cable splitter is needed. Even though the tuner had a cable IN and OUT, Chater states to not use it and instead use a cable splitter. Seems one cable should go to the Tivo (or which ever set top box is being used) and the other to the digital tuner. The tuner uses that cable to communicate to Charter what channel is requested and should be sent at which point the Tivo "sees" it with the cable plugged into it.</p>

<p>In addition to the above being done by myself. I was also on the phone with support and found out that the cable cards were set up in the system by the installer with the information switched. Meaning card A has the serial for card B and vice versa. Thus they were unable to properly decrypt anything. Once the awesome woman on the other end was able to switch those. Bingo! Working cable...finally!</p>

<p>I was tempted to put everything back the way it was and have them try to figure it out themselves when they were suppose to come out on Friday. However I decided my time was more important and simply cancelled the appointment.</p>

<p>Hope your cable installation is much easier than mine!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doing the Hard Way, 15 Miles at a Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2013/01/05/doing-the-hard-way-15-miles-at-a-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T16:03:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2013/01/05/doing-the-hard-way-15-miles-at-a-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I was suppose to go for a 15 mile run with my run group in Santa Monica. As luck would have it, I was unable to fall asleep. I got to bed early like a good little runner. However I simply laid in bed unable to fall asleep. Eventually I got out of bed at 1 or 2am and watched a little tv. Still not sleepy. I even had a glass of scotch which kinda made me sleepy, so I got back into bed. Nope.</p>
<a class="anchor" id="read-more"></a>
<p>It was now 3:30am and I'm laying there ticked off and worried how I'm going to get enough sleep to be able to get up in 2 hours. I start to think about sleeping in and simply driving over to my personal spot in Santa Monica to do a private run later in the day. However I think it will mess up my day and I didn't want to do that. I then thought, "Why not run now?" Ugh. I so didn't want to do that. I had lots of reasons why I shouldn't do that. However it was the realization that this was the least desirable choice. I decided because of that, I had to do it.</p>

<p>There have been plenty of things that have caused me to have this viewpoint. One of the biggest is when training for a marathon (not only LA but also Germany) there is the physical training is actually pretty easy...you just run. It's the mental that's much harder and difficult. If I'm resisting doing something and there is no logical reason other than, "I don't want to", "I'm tired" or other such bullshit excuses. Then I have to do it. I'm trying to get my body AND mind strong. Not only when it comes with running but with other new and difficult things that can be scary. The most notable being working on my screenplays.</p>

<p>With that decision I'm up and walking to the car at 4am to drive to Santa Monica. On the way as I'm getting on the 405 my car has an alarm go off which causes me to jump and figure out what the hell is happening. I look down and see my car is warning me that outside has gotten to be 37 degrees. The last time that warning went off I was driving up a mountain covered in snow. I then watched as the temperature dropped down to 33 degrees right in front of my eyes. Seriously within seconds. That was exactly the time a voice popped in my head and asked, "Um...Kevin, are you sure you want to go running?" To which I simply responded to that voice with, "Wimp."</p>

<p>I get to the school parking lot where our group meets and parked on the street since no one was there, obviously. I then proceeded to get ready to go for my run while being amazed just how errie quiet the street was. I get bundled up as much as I could and make my way to the boardwalk. I see cops sitting in their car on the boardwalk probably looking at this crazy guy going for a run when everyone else is trying to get away from the bone chilling cold. I turn the other way and start on my run.</p>

<p>After about a half mile I have a minivan driving on the boardwalk behind me. I move to the side to let him by even though cars aren't suppose to be driving on it unless you are a cop. The minivan kept it's distance which then caused me to start to hear that voice again, "You stupid freaking idiot. We are going to get killed all because you couldn't freaking sleep. Or worse, we're going to get raped." The only response I could muster, "We are so NOT going to get raped, with all the spandex and layers we have on, they will lose any erection before they can unhook your water belt." Thankfully right at that time the police threw their sirens on and pulled the minivan over. I looked back and simply think it was either a drunk or maybe lost guy unable to figure out how to get to another street and mistook it for a side street.</p>

<p>I then proceeded to run for 15 miles. 15 BONE CHILLING CRAZY FUCKING MILES. Holy shit what the hell was I thinking?!</p>

<p>It wasn't so bad at first. Except with time and different directions I would get the wind in my face which did NOT feel good. Add on top of the sweat soaked clothes I was wearing. I was seriously considering quitting to head back home for the safety of my warm bed. To which I had another fun conversation with myself and bitch slapped him into manning up and seeing it to the end.</p>

<p>Then something funny started to happen...the sun started to rise. Not only did it give me some motivation to continue as well as pride that I had stuck it through the darkness to literally "see the light". Then the funny part, I started to fall apart. My face was numb, my legs were sore, my feet hurt and I was freezing to my core. I wanted to quit but I was about 2 or more miles away from my car. So I did what I would like to think what anyone else would do. No I didn't call a taxi, I reached down and ran another mile further. When I hit mile 12 I was so damn happy. I could turn around and head back and run the 3 miles back to my car.</p>

<p>Strangely this was the hardest part even though it was warming up and was starting to look like a beautiful day. All I could do was think about how I was feeling and didn't like it. Knowing I had 3 miles to go and no way to magically make them faster or fly to my car, I found my mind wandering. I was listening to a screenwriting podcast on my iPod (by the way...highly recommend the Scriptnotes podcast) and found myself thinking of my screenplay. Next thing I know I'm getting ideas of the structure and story and have forgotten all about the running hell I'm putting myself through. Then my GPS watch beeps and tells me I'm done. 15 miles and 2,200+ calories burned.</p>

<p>I made my way back to my car and the school parking lot thinking I'll hit the bathroom before heading home. Only to find that they lock the gates while the groups run. By this time they had started their runs about 20 minutes prior. I was too exhausted or cold to care. At this point if I pissed myself while in my car I could have cared less. I just wanted to be warm and dry. I stripped down and got dry clothes on and headed back home. Not before stopping at a restaurant to inhale french toast, eggs and sausage.</p>

<p>I got home and then proceeded to fall on my bed, fully ready to sleep. Guess it only took running 15 miles in freezing cold.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riding the Roller Coaster Again]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2012/12/02/riding-the-roller-coaster-again/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-02T07:48:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2012/12/02/riding-the-roller-coaster-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For quite a few weeks I’ve been taking a screenwriting class at UCLA. When I first started I wondered what exactly I would get out of it. I knew I needed it. I just didn’t know how much. I was having issues with my scripts but without any experience or insight by others, I thought I was merely going through what others go through. I simply had to push through it. However there was a time when it just wasn’t feeling right. Something wasn’t clicking inside of my gut that things were operating on all cylinders. That is when I decided I was letting ego get in the way and needed to seek help. It was the best thing I could have done.
<br />
<a class="anchor" id="read-more"></a>
<br />
One of the best lessons I have learned is: “Work smarter not harder”. It has served me greatly in my work as a Software Engineer as well as a normal guy that is asked to fix every computer, phone or gizmo that some friend, family member or girlfriend is having an issue with. What I learned was I was working harder and NOT smarter when it came to writing. In order to work smarter you have to know how things can be done. Otherwise how would you know the possible ways to do something smarter? I only knew one way and that was the way I was doing it. It didn’t matter if it was the best or fastest or even smartest way. It was the only way. Well that’s just plain stupid.
<br />
<br />
What I started to learn in class was the other ways one could write. Let me rephrase that, what I learned was how a <strong>working</strong> screenwriter that gets <strong>paid</strong> for his work goes about creating it. Not the type of bullshit you read in a book. But the nuts and bolts and nitty gritty of each particular step that had or should be taken. What came later was not what I was expecting. Writer’s block. Sitting there staring at a blank page or worse starting to go down a path for the last few hours only to rip it up and throw it away when you reread it.
<br />
<br />
I was frustrated beyond belief. I typed an email to my teacher expressing my frustrating and sent it with thoughts of quitting and other self doubt. The response I got from my teacher was simple, <em>“Welcome to being a writer”</em>. It was then I learned I was going through the same things that others do. No longer am I fighting a fight that I don’t need to but I’m fighting the dragon that every artist deals with. The fight <strong>you need</strong> to be fighting. That is finding the art in the artist.
<br />
<br />
There have been some good days and bad days. More often than not there have been bad days with trying to write. However it was very recently, last week actually, that I made a breakthrough. Problems I was having with my story, not seeing things, characters or story…started to fall into place. I started to see the big picture and not only was I seeing it, I was liking it and starting to see how to craft it to what I wanted it to be. Knowing how life works I know this isn’t permanent. This will change and I will find myself fallen off the peak of inspiration and into the valley of blank pages. At that point I hope I will also remember that will also not last forever and soon I will be back on the path back up to the peak that I am at currently.
<br />
<br />
Which isn’t that all that life is? A ride to visit the peaks and valleys of ones life. I think I’m going to treat it like a roller coaster. Because the entire time I’m on it, I’m smiling. Even when I get off the ride, I’m smiling. Looking around at others asking them, “Want to do it again?”
<br />
<br />
Everyone should be living in a way that when they are at the end of their ride, they are not only asking that same question, they are answering, Yes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking Steps Forward to Your Dream]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2012/10/22/taking-steps-forward-to-your-dream/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T21:45:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2012/10/22/taking-steps-forward-to-your-dream</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“As long as you are taking steps forward it is excellent, if you are in a lull where all you do is pay bills and don’t take any steps to follow your dreams then you are doing it wrong. Whatever your dream is it requires the help of a lot of people, and you can find financing for what you are passionate about if you connect. There are infinite excuses not to do something and only you understand the real reasons to actually do it. So many people give up and start “facing reality” which is a way of saying that they don’t have enough capacity and self discipline to make their dreams come true. When you know what you want, the whole world appears as if it helps you get it, your perspective is shifted to that channel. If you are focused on paying bills then all you will see is the bills, but when you are focused on your dream then the bills are just part of your administration and organization.”</p>

<p>-Ezra Masri, TED Talks Organizer (TED website)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hating White People]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2012/10/14/hating-white-people/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T04:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kevinlinder.com/articles/2012/10/14/hating-white-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>They tried to get me to hate white people, but someone would always come along and spoil it.</p>

<p>-Thelonious Monk</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>